等等 我们不该 这么做
Wait.Wait, we shouldn't-- we shouldn't be doing this.
你玩得不开心?
What, you're not having fun?
不 只是
It's not that.It's just--
更喜欢男生?
rather be with the boys?
不
No.
那就来嘛
Well, then, come on.
需要帮助么?
You kids need any help?
不 我们没事
No.No, we're fine.
- 车子故障?,- 不是
- Car trouble?,- no.
那你们为什么在这里?
Then why are you here?
只是说说话
Um...we're just talking.
都是她在说吗?
Does she do all the talking?
差不多
Uh, most of it.
我知道这回事
I know what that's like.
十分钟后 我再回来
I'm gonna come back through here in ten minutes.
要是你们还在这儿 我就通知家长
And if you're still here,I'm gonna call your parents.
谢谢你
Yes, sir.Thank you.
到哪儿了?
Now, where were we?
我们得走了
Uh, we were going.
9分钟后再走
In nine minutes.
等等
Wait a minute.
Stevie 出什么事?
Stevie? What's wrong?
噢 老天!
Oh, my god!
救命 有人帮忙吗?
Help!Someone help me!
第三季 第13集 "草垛寻针尖","Needle in a Haystack"
House Season 3 Episode 13,"Needle in a Haystack"
"J.Whitner 医生"
"J.Whitner.M.D"
"House 医生"
"House.M.D"
十六岁的病人呼吸停止
16-year-old with respiratory arrest.
比小偷更可气的是残废小偷
The only thing I hate more than a thief is a crippled thief.
我也这么想 无外伤,没有哮喘或过敏史
Yeah, me too.No sign of trauma.No history of asthma or allerg--
- 到底谁是J.Whitner?,- 不知道
- who the hell is J.Whitner?,- No idea.
Stevie的心电图,和超声波心动图正常 但--
Stevie lipa's ekg and echocardiogram were normal, but--
正常就好 让他回家
normal is good.Send him home.
J.Whitner 医生
J.Whitner!Doctor.
他是谁 哪儿能找到他?
Who is he and where do I find him?
她是新来的研究员,为Ereshevsky工作
She's a new researcher, works with ereshevsky.
迷人吗?
Is she hot?
她坐轮椅
She's in a wheelchair.
并不表明她不迷人
Doesn't mean she's not hot.
就因为她不能弯腰,Cuddy就要折腰
Just means she can't bend over, so cuddy has to bend over backwards.
16岁孩子 检查发现血性胸腔积液
16-year-old kid.E.R.Work-up revealed a bloody pleural effusion.
奇怪
That's odd.
我也这么觉得
Yeah, that occurred to me.
你花这么久才提到?
What took you so long to mention it?
CT(断层摄影)未发现肿块和肺炎
No tumors or pneumonia on the ct.
他在亲热时昏厥
He passed out while making out.
要是他热衷于性,那也少不了毒品和摇滚乐
If he's into sex, drug and rock and roll can't be that far behind--
我猜吸食可卡因
I'm guessing cocaine.
毒物筛检没有发现
Tox screen was clean.
他当时未用 不代表他从不用毒品
just means he wasn't on drugs,,not that he hasn't been using drugs.
我看是个管道活
Looks like a plumbing problem to me.
血管渗漏
Leaky pipes.
如果动脉瘤破裂 他进停尸房了,而不是送来急诊室
If he popped an aneurysm,,he'd be in the morgue, not the E.R.
所以你得做静脉造影,而不是动脉x光片
That's why you're gonna do a venogram instead of an arteriogram.
不是高压破裂 而是低压渗漏
This is not a high-pressure burst--it's a low-pressure leak.
仍可能是毒品让血管腐蚀了
Still could have been drugs that caused,the pipes to corrode in the first place.
去查查他的床垫
So go look under his mattress.
看看有没有藏着药片 粉末和润滑剂
See if he's got any pills or powder stashed with the hand lotion.
漂亮坐骑
Sweet ride.
我也祈愿要一个带U型靠背和座垫的
I asked for the one with the sissy bar and the banana seat,
哪知圣诞老人只给我了这个
but santa gave me this instead.
这就是调皮捣蛋的下场
Guess that's what I get for being naughty.
你一定是House医生
You must be dr.House.
是
Yeah.
停车管理处有些事搞错了
So, looks like there's been some sort of mix-up at the parking office.
他们不得不给我安排近门的停车位
They had to move me closer to the door.
不得不 你不像是持械威胁的主
Had to?You don't look like the type to pull a weapon.
- 轮椅,- 拐杖
- Wheelchair.,- Cane.
我觉得你该光明磊落地,把我的位子还给我
I think you should do the honorable thing, let me have my space back.
既然你说得这么客气--,轮椅
Oh, well, uh, since you asked so nicely--wheelchair.
拐杖 走长路腿会疼
Cane!Walking long distances makes my leg hurt.
难道我就容易了?
And it's easy for me?
当然不
'Course not.
扳动摇控杆 你的拇指肌一定酸痛
Pushing that little lever, your thumb muscles must burn.
那最后10码肯定是种折磨
I'm sure the last ten yards are pure torture.
穿过停车场很危险 车子看不见我
Crossing the parking lot's dangerous--cars can't see me.
你有没有试过 在薄冰拄拐杖?
Did you ever hit a patch of black ice with a cane?
天 没有 只因我不能走路!
No, gosh, on account of the fact that I can't walk!
也许你该向停车管理处要几个鞋钉
Maybe you should ask the parking office for some crampons.
问题在于谁能更轻易地穿过停车场
Look, this is about who can most easily cross the parking lot.
你胜出
You're the winner.
奖品显然就是停车位
Oh, and the prize is apparently a parking space.
你父母的手机都没有应答
there's still no answer at either one of your parents' cell numbers.
还没有其他方法能联系到他们?
Is there any other way we might be able to contact them?
不 他们去开会
No.They're in a conference.
也许得关闭手机
They probably had to turn them off or something.
他们在哪儿不重要
What does it matter where they are?
他很疼 你得做些什么
I mean, he's in pain.You gotta do something.
必须得到他们签字
We need them to sign this.
他为什么不能签?
Why can't he just sign the papers?
- 他16岁了,- 还不是成年人
- He's 16.,- Still not an adult.
那打电话给我父母
Then call my parents.
他们认识
They know him.
他们会按规矩负责的
They'll take responsibility, do whatever you need.
不行
I can'T.It won't--
你不能让他坐着受苦,直到他父母最终决定--
you can't just let him sit here in agony until his parents finally decide--
Leah 没事
leah.It's okay.
不
No, it's not.
我感觉像有铁砧压着我的胸
I feel like there's an anvil sitting on my chest.
你赢
You win.
现在就做静脉造影
We're doing the venogram now.
过后再争执
We'll deal with the fall out later.
手指觉得湿乎乎
My fingers feel wet.
那是造影剂
That's just the dye.
神经分辨不出这是体内
Your nerves can't tell the difference between the cold inside
还是体外的冷
your body and the wet outside your body.
神经无法分辨 还是大脑不能解读?
The nerves can't tell the difference, or the brain can't interpret the difference?
两者皆有
It's a little of both.
你喜欢科学?
You like science?
是扩散式样
It looks like a diffusion pattern.
因为是低压的静脉
That's because it's the venous side, low pressure.
适用格锐目定律?,(扩散速率与温度 压力 密度的关系)
So graham's law applies?
你已经学物理了?
You've taken physics al ready?
只是自己看看书
No.Just sort of read up on my own.
有很多我也是自学
I had to teach myself a lot of stuff too.
我念的学校糟透了
Schools sucked where I grew up.
你读私立还是公立学校?
You go to public or private?
公立
Public.
是我肺静脉上有穿孔 是吗?
Leak has to be in the pulmonary veins to get in my lungs, right?
- 是,- 我看不出 你呢?
- Yep.,- I don't see anything.Do you?
- 没,- 没道理
No.It doesn't make sense.
没有出血 怎么会有积液?
How can I have a bloo effusion without any bleeding?
脏死了
This is putrid.
在检查事项中加入食物寄生虫和传染病
Put food-borne parasites and infections on the list to check on.
我去查卧室
I'll take the bedroom.
抱歉 我不知道有人在 只是
I'm sorry, I didn't know there was anyone-- we were just--
我有枪
I have a gun.
你要什么随便拿
Look, you can take whatever you want.
- 钱包在衣服里,- 别动!
- My wallet's in my suit.,- Freeze!
我报警了
Oh!I'm calling the cops.
你没有枪
Okay, you don't have a gun.
你也不会报警
And you're not calling the cops.
我会报警 除非你们立马走
Oh, no,I'm calling the cops, unless you two get out of here right now.
除非?
Unless?
要等到入室盗贼干了什么才报警?
Who calls the cops unless a burglar does something?
你是不想把风流事捅出去
You don't want to have to explain the affair.
我们不是偷情
We're not having an affair.
他戴着戒指 你没有
He's got a ring.You don'T.
由楼下厨房的情形
And judging from the state of the kitchen downstairs
和打扫了一半的卧室判断
and the half-vacuumed bedroom,
我猜你做情人好过做女佣
I'm guessing you're a better lover than you are a maid.
女佣?
Maid?
你这浑小子
You son of a bitch.
我不是女佣
I'm not a maid, okay?
这是我的房子 不是他的
This is my house, not his.
对不起
Oh, sorry.
厨房有什么不对了?
And what's wrong with my kitchen?
没什么 很抱歉
Nothing.We're sorry.
我们是想帮Stevie
We're just here to help stevie.
谁是Stevie?
Who's stevie?
你的 儿子?
Your...son?
什么?
Huh?
地址是你给的
it was the address you gave.
肯定是急诊室写错了
The E.R.Must have written it down wrong.
不想让我们找到你父母,所以你胡诌
Or you lied because you don't want us to talk to your parents.
我把电话号码都给你们了
I gave you their phone numbers.
你是给了号码
you gave us some numbers.
联系不上任何人
We haven't been able to reach anyone.
说过了 他们一定是在开会
I told you,they must be in a conference.
他说谎
He's lying.
Leah.
Leah
他是罗马尼人
He's romani.
吉普赛人
A gypsy.
你没有家?
So you don't have a home?
当然有
Of course we do.
接下来你要问营火舞蹈,还是偷窃幼童?
Next you're gonna ask me about dancing around campfires and-- Stealing children?
这就是我不对人说的原因
This is why I don't tell people.
他们自己人之间分享所有,对外人戒心很深
They share everything with each other and nothing with the gadje-- the outsiders.
和外人交流 没给我的族人带来好结果
Sharing information with outsiders has not gone so well for my people.
我明白 可你对我们撒谎 会让病情恶化
I get it, but right now you're making yourself more vulnerable by lying to us.
你们不能去我家
You can't go to my house.
会污染它
You'll pollute it.
我们只是检查一下
All we're gonna do is look around.
你们到场就足够危害
Your presence is enough.
我父母对这很看重
My parents take it seriously.
不管是精神还是肉体
It's spiritual as much as it is physical.
你知道他住在哪儿?
You know where he lives?
别说
Don'T.
我什么都告诉你们
Look, I'll tell you whatever you need to know.
- 如果对你的回答无法取信,- 我有时候喝酒
If we can't trust your answers-- I drink sometimes, okay?
我吸过大麻
I've smoked pot.
我什么都说
I'll tell you anything.
实话
The truth.
你们不能去我家
You just-- You can't go in my home.
大麻不会导致出血
The pot wouldn't cause a bleeding problem.
但大麻上的杀虫剂会
A pesticide on the pot could.
你从哪儿得到的?
Where did you get it?
学校里一孩子
Some kid at school.
Stevie 大麻是我给他的
stevie.He got the pot from me.
他不上学
He doesn even go to school.
他父母让他辍学了
His parents made him drop out.
家庭教学
I'm home schooled.
他看书
He reads books.
还说了什么谎话?
What else are you lying about?
你父亲真是教授?
Is your father really a professor?
他是推销员
He's a salesman.
能到手的任何东西 他们都买卖
They buy and sell anything they can get their hands on.
他们 你和你爸爸一起做买卖
they--so you're with your dad when he's making these deals?
他上个星期才到芝加哥
He was just in chicagoa week ago.
乘飞机?
You fly?
不 我爸爸有货车
No.My dad's got a truck.
你不是认真的吧
You can't be serious.
我当真
Actually, I can.
我的地盘得要回来
See?It's my space.I want it back.
不是你的车位
It's not your space.
是医院的车位
It's the hospital's space.
院方认为 处境困难的人应享好位置
And the hospital thinks that the person who's worse off should get the better space.
你在残障人士停车位申请中提到,你能走50码
Your application for a handicapped space says you can walk 50 yards.
Whitner说她每换一次机油能驶上50英里
And whitner says she can roll 50 miles between oil changes.
我可换不了腿
I can't change my leg.
我把你换到离前门46码的地方
The space I moved you to is only 46 yardsaway from the front door.
我量过 你没问题
I measured.You'll be fine.
好么 那我走入大厅4码再瘫倒,胜过倒在雪地上
Great--so I can collapse four yards into the lobby instead of outside in the cold.
只要你不在我办公室倒下就行
As long as it's not in my office.
你知道谁一连6年赢得纽约市马拉松大赛?
You know who won the new york city marathon six years in a row?
坐轮椅一哥们
Guy in a wheelchair.
那你也弄个轮椅坐 别来烦我
Then go get yourself one and leave me alone.
还我车位 我乐得整天滚来滚去
Gimme my space, I'll be happy to roll around all day.
你坐轮椅坚持不了一星期
You couldn't last one week in a wheelchair.
想打赌?
Wanna bet?
你怎么了?
What's wrong with you?
一周不用腿,万事皆解决
Nothing that a week off my feet won't solve.
静脉造影没有发现渗漏
venogram's negative.No leak.
你是说没找到渗漏?
You mean you couldn't find the leak.
你的腿恶化了?
is your leg worse?
不 是我的车位遇险
No, but my parking spot is.
血液只应存在于循环系统中
Blood is only made inside the circulatory system,
要是在外面发现了
which means when we find it outside--
没有渗漏 淋巴腺我也查了
there's no leak.I even checked lymphatics.
你坐一周的轮椅
So you're gonna spend a weekin a wheelchair
就是为了得到离门近的车位?
just to get a parking space closer to the front door?
比起把腿剁下来可简单多了
Easier than chopping off my legs.
排除了毒素和毒品
We've ruled out toxins and drugs.
一定程度上 他是罗马尼人
kind of.He's romani.
不得不保守秘密
Apparently, they feel the need to keep secrets,
很难确证任何事
so it's hard to know anything for sure.
他也是个人
Yeah, he's also a human being,
一开始就不该相信他
which means you shouldn't be trusting him to begin with.
别依赖他给出答案 你们得自己找
Stop relying on his answers and find some on your own.
这是深静脉血栓
It's a deep veinthrombosis.
这孩子在车子后座上待了16个小时
The kid spent 16 hours in the backseat of an old pickup.
导致了血液凝块 行到了肺部
Causes a clot and makes its way to his lungs.
该做动脉X光摄影 找到凝块,用tpa(组织纤溶酶原)溶栓
We should do an arteriogram,find the clot, bust it with tpa.
或者找出渗漏
Or we could find the leak.
没有渗漏
There's no leak.
你不该对坐轮椅的嚷嚷
Hey, you can't yell at a guy in a wheelchair.
缓慢的渗漏
It's a slow leak.
让它加速
You gotta speed it up.
稀释血液 重做静脉造影
Thin his blood. Redo the venogram.
那会导致大出血
That could cause a massive bleed.
好极了 大出血就更好找了
Excellent--massive'll beeven easier to find.
借过
Pardon me.
看来你们得乘下一部了
Guess you guys are gonna have to get the next one.
我以为你们要做静脉造影
I thought you were redoing the venogram.
等做完动脉造影之后
As soon as we're done with the arteriogram.
你会觉得被扎了下
Okay, you're gonna feel a little poke.
能不能你来做?
Could you maybe do that?
放心 只是你的腿
don't worry.It's just your leg.
我不会更进一步
I don't have to go any further than this.
看这个
take a look at this.
你前臂的骨头
Bones of your forearm.
桡骨和尺骨
Uh, radius and ulna.
手腕这儿呢?
How 'bout the wrist?
月骨 钩骨
Um...lunate...hamate...the...
惊慌的情人尝试高难度姿势,(SLTPTTCH 腕部骨骼首字母缩写)
scared lovers try positions they can't handle.
这是我记忆腕骨的方法
It's a mnemonic for the wrist bones.
唯一能记住它们的方法
It's the only way I can remember them.
怎么了?
Are you okay?
我的胃
Ow.Ow, my stomach.
你碰到什么?
You hit something?
- 才刚开始,- 躺平
- I barely started.,- Lie flat.
不行 太疼了
No, I can'T.It hurts too much.
我抽出来
I'm getting out.
这是看清楚的唯一机会
It's our only chance to see what's going on.
如果他动 我会刺破动脉
If he moves,I could shred his artery.
拿出来 马上
Just get it out!Now!
没事的 Stevie
It's gonna be okay, stevie.
注入造影剂
Just inject the dye.
造影剂进入了肝脏 却没有出来
Dye's going into his liver,but it's not coming out.
血凝块一定压迫了肝静脉
The clot's gonna be constricting the flow in the hepatic vein.
不是压迫
It's not constricting it.
而是完全阻塞了
It's completely blocking it.
肝脏一塌糊涂
His whole liver's fried.
孩子的肝脏衰竭 因肝静脉严重阻塞
kid's liver's failing because of massive clots blocking his hepatic vein.
他怎么可能既出血又有血栓?
How can he have both a bleed and a clot?
不是血栓
It's not a clot.
肯定是导管丝堵住了静脉
Must have blocked a vein with a catheter wire.
不可能
Not a chance.
下游血压高也可能阻碍血流
Increased pressure downstream could also stop the blood.
没有心脏衰竭和肝硬化
there's no heart failure or cirrhosis.
说明一定是血栓
Means it has to be a clot.
严重的血栓堵住了静脉
Massive clots block veins.
这不会导致渗漏
They don't make them leak.
鉴于他明显有--
And since he clearly has some kind of--
你有小麻烦?
you having a little problem?
你介意帮个手?
Would you mind?
真是羞辱
Boy, that was humiliating.
不知道Whitner日子怎么过的?
How does whitner make it through the day?
骄兵必败
"Pride goeth before the fall.
还好 我有个宝贝椅坐
" Lucky for me, I'm sittingin one of these babies.
还有什么等我驳斥的理论?
So, what other theories can I shoot down?
DIC(弥散性血管内凝血)能解释
Dic would explain both--
血小板正常,PTT(凝血酶活时间)也没有提高
his platelets are normal and his ptt isn't elevated.
白血病?
Leukemia?
全血球和分类计数无异常
Normal cbc and differential.
该像水管工一样思考时,你们怎么还摆医生的谱
You guys are still thinking like doctors when you should be thinking like plumbers.
快 给我点带劲的
Come on, I wanna see some butt crack.
肝脏里什么东西在血管上扎了洞
Something inside the liver is punching holes in the pipes.
血从开口渗出 粘在异物上 造成了血块
Blood bleeds through the opening, sticks to the intruder,forms a mass.
- 血栓,- 血块
- A clot.,- A mass.
癌症 肿瘤能腐蚀血管
cancer.A tumor could erode a blood vessel.
肺结核肉状瘤形成肉芽肿也可能
well, so could a granuloma from tuberculosisor sarcoidosis.
做CT MRI(核磁共振),痰液检查和血管紧张素转换酶水平
Do a ct, mri, a sputum,and an ace level.
借过
excuse me, sorry.
瘸子来了
Cripple coming through.
他说喉咙痛
He says his throat hurts.
从用词看 你觉得不是
That phrasing means you think it doesn'T.
不是
No, I don'T.
我走运了
Good enough for me.
你去哪里?
Where are you going?
妈妈懂得多
Mothers know best.
出去时自己拿个棒棒糖
Get yourself a sucker on the way out.
我认为他是为了不去上学而装病
Look, I think he's just faking so he doesn't have to go to school.
你看我像检查逃学的训导员吗?
How did you know I was a truant officer?
我跟他说 不去学校就得看医生
I told him he had a choice--go to school or the doctor.
他浪费你时间 你就来浪费我的
Right--he's wasting your precious time, so you decided to waste mine.
多体贴
How thoughtful.
我坐轮椅 他坐上面检查不到
I'm in a wheelchair, so I can't examine him all the way up there.
跳下来
Hop down.
我的人生就是一难接一难
My life is just one horror after another.
张嘴
Open.
看着是肿痛么?
Does it look like it hurts?
没有
Nope.
- 这是什么,- 注射器
- What's that?,- It's a syringe.
我是帮你 让他讨厌医生甚于学校
I'm with you--make him hate the doctor's office more than he hates school.
够了
That's okay.
不认为--
I don't--I don't think that's--
只是盐水 直接注射进肌肉痛得要命
it's just saline--hurts like hell when it's injected directly into the muscle.
你看是胳膊还是屁股?
So what do you think?Arm or ass?
我想他学乖了
I think he's learned his lesson.
我不觉得
Oh, I don't know.
最好检查下
We better check.
Jack 你妈妈是不是大蠢蛋?
Jack, is your mommy a big fat idiot?
瞧吧
Well, what do you know?
看来你是对的
Guess you were right.
保持不动 Stevie
Just hold still, stevie.
不会很久
This shouldn't take long.
我想这里的麦克风收不到点头状
Sorry, i'm guessing the mike in this thing doesn't pick up nods.
聪明孩子
Smart kid.
可惜会浪费了
Too bad it's all gonna go to waste.
当个推销员没什么不好
Nothing wrong with being a salesman.
他该追求自己的生活
He should be able to pursue his own life,
而不是帮父母卖旧烤箱
not be stuck helping his parents sell old toasters.
他还年轻 没法预料以后什么样?
He's still young--you never know what he'll end up doing.
除非他回学校,不然我很清楚他将来什么样
Unless he goes back to school, I know exactlywhat he'll end up doing.
等等
Wait.
这是不是伤口?
Is that a lesion?
放大五倍
magnifying times five.
是肉芽肿
it's a granuloma.
韦格纳肉芽肿病最有可能
Means wegener's is most likely.
Stevie!
妈 是你吗?
Mom, is that you?
嘿!
hey, hey!
让他马上出来
Get him out of this now!
你儿子病了
Your son is sick.
门上的标牌--
The sign on the door--
标牌说不能带有金属物
no, the sign says no metal.
我们都取下了
We took everything off.
是说不得入内
It says no admittance.
我儿子怎么了?
What's wrong with our son?
还不清楚
We don't know yet.
他不会死 是吗?
He's not gonna die, is he?
你儿子病得很重
Your son is very ill.
还在查病因
We're still trying to figure out why,
所以需要你们出去
which is why we need you to leave the room.
你准备怎么做?
what are you going to do now?
我要把屁股从这个座位挪到那个
Oh, now I've gotta slide my butt from one padded seat to another.
要是碰伤膝盖怎么办?
What if I bump my knee?
核磁共振在他的肺部发现肉芽肿
Mri showed a granulomain his liver.
棒极了
Fantastic.
帮个忙怎么样?
Wanna give me a hand here?
不 血凝 出血 肉芽肿表明了是韦格纳病
No--clotting, bleeding, and a granuloma equals wegener'S.
我知道 所以才说棒极了
I know.That's why I said fantastic.
我可是真诚的
I was being sincere.
帮我一把
Now give me a hand.
那不公平
It wouldn't be fair.
准备活检肝脏来证实
We're gonna biopsy the liver to confirm.
你不帮忙才不公平
Wouldn't be fair not to.
人是好心 仁慈 友善的,会帮助坐轮椅的人
People are good and kind and gentle and help people in wheelchairs.
你才不信这一套
You don't believe that.
- 可你信,- 不 我不信
- But you do.,- No, I don'T.
Foreman.
Foreman
别做活检
Forget the biopsy.
在得出结论前 他肝脏就不行了
His liver'll be gone before you get the results.
给他用环磷酰胺(免疫抑制剂),在韦格纳病于另一根血管上钻孔前
Start treatment with cyclophosphamide before wegener's punches a hole in another pipe.
衣服怎么回事?
What's with the clothes?
你还不能出院
You're not being discharged.
我知道 是我父母
I know.It-- it's my parents.
他们一定要我穿
They insist that I wear this stuff.
坚持用我们的食物-,衣服 陈设是有原因的
We insist on our own food,gown, and furnishings for a reason.
我的胸痛
Hey, my--my chest burns.
你确定治疗作用了?
Are you sure the treatments are working?
韦格纳病使机体自我攻击
Wegener's causes the body to attack itself.
不会一夜间好转
It doesn't get undone overnight.
耐心点
Be patient.
你的汤呢?
Where's your soup?
垃圾桶里
It's in the garbage.
有柳树皮汁
It has willow bark extract.
柳树皮汁基本上就是阿司匹林
Willow bark extract is basically aspirin.
是 对付发热
Yes, for the fever.
他已经在用药了 我们的药物
He's already on meds--our meds.
可不想有不良冲突反应
We can't risk any adverse interactions.
这些东西都得拿走
We need all this stuff to go.
我们必需控制环境
We need to control this environment.
我们也是
So do we.
人得病是有原因的
People get sick for a reason.
因他们的生活失去平衡
'Cause something in their life is out of balance.
爸爸 他是医生
Dad, he's a doctor.
他不想听你说教
He doesn't want to hear your talk.
那女孩走了 平衡就开始重建
Balance is just starting to be restored now that that girl is gone.
你们不在时,你们儿子可全靠她照顾
That girl took pretty good care of your son while you were away.
我们领教了
Yes, we can see that.
这些能让他感觉自在些
All this stuff may make him feel more comfortable,
- 但--,- 治疗要花多长时间?
- but it's not--,- how long is this treatment gonna take?
很快就应该能看到他肝功能有起色
We should start to see some improvement in his liver function soon.
"很快" 科学的词
"Soon."Very scientific.
对不起
I'm sorry.
一会儿回来给你检查
Be back in a little bit to check on you.
啊 来了
ah, yes.
这不是Ironside医生,(Ironside:一电视剧中坐轮椅的侦探)
If it isn't dr.Ironside.
不是医生
Ah, if isn't "dr.
我小时候没有朋友
I had no friends when I was growing up,
老是一个人看电视
"so all I did was watch tv by myself,
所以我如今能旁征博引通俗文化
"which is why I can now make constant pop culture references
除了我 没人听得明白
which no one understands but me.
这是我的名字 别叫破了,(出自音乐电影Grease的一句台词)
" That's my name. Don't wear it out."
躲得过Cuddy 躲不过她的党羽
Ah, ah.Safe from cuddy, but I guess not from her trusted rat-complice.
讲道理的人不会拿残疾程度来讲价钱
Reasonable people don't debate the relative merits of their handicaps.
讲道理的人定规矩靠证据
Reasonable people make rules based on evidence--
好比走50码有困难
like difficulty covering a distance, say 50 yards,
而不是依据预设的悲惨度等级
not on some pre-ordained pathetic-ness scale.
据我所知,顽固不是第八条天授美德
Last I checked,pigheadedness was not the eighth heavenly virtue.
做错了才叫顽固不化
It's only pigheaded if you're wrong.
做对了 这叫做坚持原则
If you're right, they call it sticking to your principles.
放弃吧 你这是自贬身份
Give it up.You're demeaning yourself.
有人也这么对Rosa Parks说过,(美国现代民权运动之母)
That's what they told rosa parks.
别站起来
Don't stand up in there.
我可盯着你的脚
I'm watching your feet.
离开我们家
Get out of our home.
这里不是谁的家
This is not a home.
当然不
It's certainly not--
只要我们儿子在 这儿就是我们家
it's our home as long as our son is here.
妈 爸 能不能冷静一下
Mom, dad, will you just please just calm down?
你不是家人
You're not family.
不能待在这儿
You have no right to be here.
你要做什么 把我扔出去?
What are you gonna do,throw me out?
你不能碰外族女人
You can't even touch the gadje.
我来碰你
I'll touch you.
怎么了?
What is going on?
是我送他进医院的
I'm the one who brought him here.
我有权知道他的情况
I should be able to see how he's doing.
如果不是你 他不会来这儿
He wouldn't even need to be here if it weren't for you.
是我不干净 让他的肝脏衰竭
Right--I'm so unclean,I caused his liver to shut down.
够了
Enough.
没人会被赶走
No one is leaving.
他是我们的儿子 我们要她离开
He's our son,and we want her out of here.
很疼
It hurts.
又是你的胃?
Your stomach again?
不 哪里?
No.What?
他的肝脏有了起色
his liver's actually improving.
堵住了一个孔 又捅开另一个
We plug one hole and end up poking another.
这是讨论病情还是,向Cuddy申请加薪?
We talking about the patient or how to get a raise from cuddy?
针对韦格纳病的治疗使他膀胱大出血
The wegener's treatment gave him a massive hemorrhagein his bladder.
意味着...
Which means...
是韦格纳病
it's wegener'S.
我刚说什么了?
What did I just say?
以韦格纳病来治疗 结果一切都糟糕
we were treating him for wegener's when eveverything went wrong.
并非全部
Not everything.
是 今天好天气
Yeah, it was a very lovely day outside.
可是 治疗让他情况更糟
On the other hand,the treatment made him worse.
治疗让他的膀胱变糟 不是肝
Treatment made his bladder worse, not his liver.
肝脏的凝块在消解
Clot in the liver's breaking up.
核磁共振 痰检 血管紧张素转换酶水平,排除了肺结核 肉状瘤
And the mri, sputum, and ace ruled out tb, sarcoidosis,
和淋巴瘤 只剩下
and lymphoma, which leaves us with...
仍可能是癌症--
still could be a cancer with multiple--
用核磁共振 断层摄影 验血,都没检查出的癌症?
a cancer we can't see on mri, ct, or blood tests?
是韦格纳病
It's wegener'S.
并非诊断错了
It's not the wrong diagnosis.
而是治疗有误
It's the wrong treatment.
可以加强对免疫系统抑制
We could increase immuno suppression.
用上甲氨蝶呤
Add methotrexate.
不能给肺有问题的孩子用甲氨喋呤
we can't give methotrexate to a kid who's already had lung problems.
甲氨喋呤地毯式轰炸
Methotrexateis carpet bombing.
什么炸飞了
Hits everything.
我们需要精确制导炸弹
We need a smart bomb.
不是抑制免疫系统 而是改变它
So we don't suppress the immune system-- we change it.
免疫调节
Immune modulation.
Ft-28(免疫调节剂）
Ft-28.
他的抗体攻击自身的血管
His antibodies are attacking his blood vessels.
应激导致出血和凝结
The irritation causes them to bleed and clot.
我们改变他的免疫系统使抗体
We change his immune system so the antibodies don't interact
不再攻击血管 在别处正常工作
with his blood vessels but work fine everywhere else.
Ft-28仍在试验中
Ft-28's still experimental.
没得到药监局批准
It's not fda-approved.
对克罗氏病和风湿性关节炎疗效显著
It's worked for crohn's disease and rheumatoid arthritis.
他没得克罗氏病和关节炎
He doesn't have crohn's or arthritis.
那就假设他有...
Let's say that he does...
并开始治疗
and start the treatment.
绝对不行
absolutely not.
我们族人曾被用于实验 绝不允许再发生
My people have been experimented on before.Never again.
Lipa先生 恕我直言
Mr.Lipa,with all due respect,
拿这家医院和奥斯威辛(集中营),相比太荒谬了
comparing this hospitalto auschwitz is ridiculous.
Ft-28的安全性在,几百位患者身上都得到了验证
Ft-28's been proven safe in hundreds--
人们总说自己值得信任
people always say you can trust them.
为什么不说点别的?
Why would they say anything else?
我们怎么会轻信
Why do they think we would listen--
嗨 你以为我不了解这种感受
hey, hey, hey.You think I don't understand what it's like to
来自于曾被奴役和虐待的民族
come from a people who've been enslaved, mistreated,
也曾被作为实验对象
and experimented on?
塔斯基吉实验二战后还持续了28年,(以黑人男子做梅毒实验)
Tuskegee went on for 28 years after world war ii.
禁止罗马尼人踏入这个州的法令,(吉普赛人原称罗马尼人)
And the laws that made it illegal for the romani to even set foot
直到1998年还是白纸黑字
in this state were still on the books until 1998.
这历史不算古老
It's not ancient history.
常规治疗不起作用
Conventional therapy hasn't worked.
你的儿子说不定会死的
Your son may be dying.
他需要针对性治疗 你要相信我们
He needs a targeted approach,and you need to trust us.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
毕生的经历告诫我们不能相信你
A life time of experiences tells me I can't trust you.
过去的三天也不会改变这信念
And the past three days have done nothing to change that.
我们想让儿子接受治疗 不是当作实验品
We want our son treated,not experimented on.
如果你束手无策 直说就是
If you don't know how to do that, then just tell us
我们带他到有办法的地方去
so we can take him someplace where they do.
他们做的没错
they're absolutely right.
远离未经证实 实验性的东西
Stay away from that unproven, experimental stuff.
不如执着于变换家具布置 直到他好转
Much better to stick with the "moving of furniture until he gets better" approach.
是  说的对
Yes, you're right.
我们该想出别的方案
We're gonna have to come up with something else.
这已经是没办法的办法了
You mean another last-ditch desperation move?
有还有别的主意?
You got anything?
再去说服 只许成不许败
Go back and don't take no for an answer.
你算什么推销员?
What kind a salesman are you?
我不想跟这些往窗户上贴锡纸的人打交道,(吉普赛人极度神秘)
The kind who avoids the house with the crazy couple who put tinfoil over their windows.
如果他们买得起锡纸,就有钱买你的东西
They got money for tinfoil, they got money for whatever you're selling.
什么意思?
What's that mean?
如果他们不信任你 不妨以毒攻毒
Means that if they don't trust you, you should earn that lack of trust.
付钱买锡纸什么意思?
what does paying for tinfoil mean?
我为什么要回答所有的问题?
Why should I have to answer all the questions?
哦 对不起
Oops.Sorry.
动力方向没掌握好
Still getting used to the power steering.
我想你听说了?
I assume you've heard the news?
我一点不担心
I'm not worried.
就我看来 你不知羞耻还没自制力
From what I hear,what you lack in shame you also lack in will power.
我或许意志软弱 但是骨头硬
My will may be weak, but my backbone is strong.
不拄拐杖 腿都不疼了
And pain-free, now that I've stopped using the cane.
当然瞟Cuddy的低领衫难度加大
'Course, it's harder to look down cuddy's shirt.
看她翘臀的优势显著增加
Then, the vantage point on her ass is much improved.
这就是我 永远看着光明的一面
That's just me--alwayslooking on the bright side.
我就是那个说她的C罩杯名不副实的人
I'm the guy who said that her c cups are half-full.
还真辣  不是么
They are nice,aren't they?
哦 不
Oh...no.
想讨好我不是这么容易
You're not gonna win me over that easily.
光有个轮子(坐轮椅)
You may have a wheel.
还不能上润滑油(得到通融)
It doesn't mean you get the grease.
这轮子必须吱吱作响(还要会闹事),[谚: squeak wheel gets grease]
You gotta squeak.
这是什么？
What's that?
环磷酰胺
Cyclophosphamide.
我们应你的要求用常规治疗
We're continuing the standard treatment as you requested.
请大家都离开几分钟
Uh, I have to ask everyone to leave the room for a few minutes
我好换绷带
while I apply some bandages.
为什么我们要离开？
Why do we have to leave?
为他小弟弟换
For his penis.
你说了谎
You lied to them.
已经止血了
The bleeding stopped.
我不需要绷带了
I don't need any bandages.
我们要换个方法治疗 但你父母不同意
We need to changeyour treatment, but your parentswon't let us.
他们认定我们想拿你
They've got it in their minds that we want to try
做没人性的实验
some sort of inhuman experiment on you.
实验性的治疗?
The treatment's experimental?
Ft-28已经通过大量的临床试验
Ft-28's been through extensive clinical trials.
对其他病症的治疗效果很好
It's also been used successfully for other conditions.
你建议这个
The fact that you're recommending...
实验性疗法是因为没有选择了?
experimental treatment means you haveno other options?
恐怕是
Sorry.
止住胸膜渗液 肝脏不行了
We stop the pleural effusions,your liver almost fails.
保住你的肝脏后膀胱又衰竭
We save your liver, the bladder fails.
如果不能先发制人
If we don't get ahead of the curve on this--
你想让我做什么?
what do you need me to do?
把药吃了 但是别告诉你父母
Take the medicine,but don't ll your parents.
我可不想欺骗父母
I don't like lyingto my parents.
别人可都欺骗
The rest of the world,though--
不能信任别的人
the rest of the world can't trust.
你可以相信我
You can trust me.
凭什么信你？
How do I know?
要是你服药 再告诉你父母,我的执照会被吊销
Because if you do this,then tell your parents, I lose my license.
噢 天呐!
Ow!God!
来人!
Get in here!
脾脏像爆炸了一样
wow.Spleen basically exploded, huh?
找到另一条出血血管
Got another bleeder.
2-0丝线和止血钳
2-0 silk on a stick.
好了
Got it.
您点的是生肉吗?
I believe you ordered your meat rare.
先别缝合 如果确诊是韦格纳肉芽肿病
Keep him open--if I confirm wegener's,
可以趁他在台上的时候安排手术
might as well stage the diseasewhile he's still on the table.
什么事情花这么长时间
What's taking so long?
外囊破裂但是还很完整
External capsule's ruptured but still intact.
没有血凝和出血的迹象
No signs of a clot or bleed.
小囊正常
Normal follicles.
淋巴组织正常
Normal lymphoid tissue.
他的脾脏裂成碎片了
His spleenis ripped to shreds.
那肯定有肉芽肿 继续找
There's gotta be granulomas.Keep looking.
快点
come oN.
不能把这家伙一直这么摆着
Can't leave humpty dumpty like this forever.
除了正常的脾脏我什么也没看到
I don't see anythingbut normal spleen.
没有肉芽肿
No granulomas.
也就是意味着不是韦格纳病
Means no wegener'S.
我只需要知道这些
That's all I need to know.
开始吧
Let's go, people.
顺着他的肠子找
run his bowel.
不用了
No neeD.
我在缝合了
I'm closing.
缝合线
Suture.
顺着他的肠子找
Run his bowel.
脾脏里没有什么可疑的
nothing suspiciousin the spleen.
把他弄走
Get him out of here.
你没看到
You missed it.
在他的肝脏里有一个肉芽肿
He had a granulomain his liver.
不 那只不过是疤痕组织
no, it was just scar tissue.
核磁共振看上去象肉芽肿 但是并不是
Looked like a granuloma on the mri, but it's not.
不知道这有什么需要争论的
Don't know whyI'm debating this.
把弯血管钳递给我
Pass me the kelly clamp.
缝合中
I'm closing.
甭想 除非把我的手也缝到他肚子里
Not unless you're gonna sew my hand into this kid's stomach.
别碰他
Get out of there.
他状况不稳定
He's unstable.
他有韦格纳病 意味着他有肉芽肿
He's got wegener's,which means he's got granulomas.
我要叫律师了
I'm calling my lawyer.
肠道只有26英尺长
It's only 26 feet.
如果他是鸵鸟 你得等上46英尺
If he were an ostrich,you'd have a 46-foot wait.
血压在下降
Blood pressure's dropping.
再输一袋林格溶液(复方乳酸钠溶液)
Hang another bag of ringer's lactate.
我不想做帮凶
I'm having nothing to do with this.
- Foreman 再挂一袋...,- 林格溶液 知道了
- Foreman,hang another bag--,- ringer's lactate.Got it.
快点 快点
Come on, come on.
应该有的
It's gotta be in here.
没有
But it's not.
介意我缝合么
Mind if we close?
幸好我们推销ft-28没有成功
Well, it's a good thing we never sold him on ft-28.
他父母是正确的
His parents were right.
他父母不会再让我们靠近他了
There's no way his parents are gonna let us near him again.
手术恢复之前 没法把他转移到别的医院
they won't be able to transfer him until he's recovered from the surgery.
这下手术组也不会和我们亲近了
You can add the surgical team to the list of people who won't let us near him.
出血 凝块 出血 凝块
Bleeds, clots, bleeds, clots.
脾脏爆炸了
Spleen explodes.
应该测试维勒布兰德氏病,(较少为人知的血友病类型)
We should test himfor von willebrand'S.
或者来玩一下井字棋
Or we could just play tic-tac-toe.
X代表出血
Okay, xs are bleeds.
O代表凝块
Os are clots.
从肺部开始的 对吧
We started in the lungs, right?
我们都做了什么
What did we do?
断层摄影 痰液检查 两次静脉造影
Ct, sputum, two venograms.
一次出血 一次凝块
That's one bleed, one clot.
然后呢
Then what?
肝脏停止工作
Liver shut down.
核磁共振 化验 用环磷酰胺
Mri, labs, treated with cyclophosphamide.
于是 他尿了三个单位O型阴性血
Whereupon, he peed out3 units of o negative.
另一处出血
Another bleed.
这意味着什么
Where is this going?
我也还不知道
I don't know yet.
下面怎么了
What's next?
膀胱 肾脏
Bladder, kidneys.
高解析度CT扫描
high resolution ct scan.
尿酸和尿液沉积
Ua and urine sediment.
胃肠造影?
Gi tract?
你在手术室里顺着他的小肠找了一下
You ran his small bowel in the or.
大肠被固定在腹壁上了
The large bowelis fixed to the abdominal wall.
我没有查过大肠
I didn't run that.
因为没有理由去查
Because there was no reason to.
他肠道里没有任何症状
He hasn't been having any symptoms in his bowels.
做一个结肠镜检查
Do a colonoscopy.
因为他没有任何症状?
Because he's had no symptoms?
要是钥匙丟了 四处寻找
You lose your keys,first thing you do is look everywhere
所有合情理的地方
you might logically have placed them.
没有找到 就扩大搜索范围
You don't find them, then you start looking in other places.
医药箱 冰箱 邮箱
The medicine cabinet,freezer, mailbox.
我们要去这孩子的邮箱里看看
We need to lookin this kid's mailbox.
怎么不去给他的脚做X光?
Why don't we x-ray his feet?
他的脚也没事
They're fine too.
因为要守住中间的格子啊
Because we need to take the center square to block.
好吧 就算有意义 也很难
Okay, even if that did make sense, it's kind of hard to
给你不能接近的孩子做结肠镜检查
do a colonoscopy on a kid you can't get near.
他现在在重症监护室
He's in the icu now.
他父母只有限制性探视权
His parents only have limited visiting privileges.
我喜欢这小子
I like that kid.
有胆量
He's got spunk.
现在不能聊天
Can't talk now.
在放风呢
On guard duty.
你还在坚持
You're still in that thing.
什么?
What thing?
这个
Oh, this.
习以为常了
Forgot it was even there.
即使你能躲过老天的惩罚
You know,even if you manage not to get struck down by
坚持一个礼拜 cuddy也不会给你那个车位
a bolt of lightning and make it a week, cuy's not gonna give you the space.
她不能
She can'T.
愿赌服输
Bet's a bet.
打赌比美国残疾人法案地位还要高
Yes, and that rule out ranks the americans with disabilities act.
你有你的逻辑 但是Whitner有法律支持
You think you've got logic on your side, but whitner's got the legal system.
法律每每战胜逻辑,只要看看辛普森案
And legal bets logic every time--just ask O.J.
你是正确的
You're right.
- 是吗?,- 对
I am?Yeah.
即使你知道在法律上站不住脚,还是要这么做
So you're doing this even though you know you've got no legal leg to stand on.
要是有轮子谁还要脚啊
Who needs legs when you got wheels?
我会占住那个位子
I'm gonna get that spot.
cuddy别想骗我!,(gyp: 诈骗/吉普赛人缩写 双关)
No way cuddyis going to gyp me!
你说什么?
What'd you say?
回头见
I'll see you later.
要让他们接下来二十分钟都冲我嚷嚷
Gonna have them yelling at me for the next 20 minutes.
黏膜看上去很正常 健康
Mucosa looks normal,healthy.
没有单独的肠道憩室
No lonely diverticula.
血压下降
Blood pressure's dropping.
他又出血了
He's bleeding agn.
不是结肠
not in his colon.
- 快点,- 我知道
- Hurry up.,- I am.
什么也没有
There's nothing there.
等一下 等一下 那是什么
Wait, wait, what's that?
反光?
A reflection?
不 像是根 牙签
No, it's something...looks like A...toothpick.
你确定?
Are you sure?
他一定是意外吞了下去
He must have swallowed it accidentally and
以为总归可以把它消化
just figured he'd digest it eventually.
当你们在车里亲热时
When you two were making out in the car,
肠道弯曲压迫那根牙签
it must have folded awkwardly and pushed the toothpick
穿过肠壁刺进了肺部
through the wall of the intestine and into the lung.
移动到肝部 并且前进到他的膀胱和脾脏
And it moved on to his liver and made its wayto his bladder and spleen.
就这样 他会好起来的吧
So that's it.He's gonna be okay.
对 几个小洞
Yeah.Small holes.
既然取出来了 他好起来就快了
He shouldn't take that long to heal, now that we've got it out.
瞧
See?
看你都做了些什么?
See what you did?
我?
Me?
如果你不吻他...
If you hadn't been kissing him...
你听到了这 是因为牙签!
that's what you heard?It was the toothpick!
是因为那令人恶心的习惯--
It was that disgusting habit--
要不是他扭曲身体 牙签早排出了
it would have just passed right through him if he hadn't been writhing around.
难道不对么--
Isn't that right--
- 就这个?,- 对
- that's it?,- Yeah.
就这个
That's it.
木材吸水 密度和它周围的组织一样
Wood absorbs water, becomes the same density as the tissue around it.
所以在CT和核磁共振上都看不到
That's why it didn't show upon the ct or mri.
挺酷的
That's cool.
我是吃了苦,可这么小的东西带来这么大伤害
I mean, not cool for me, but...lotta damagefor something so small.
这里的实验室 有一个带薪实习的职位
You know, the lab here, they have a paid intern position.
通常都会给大学里的孩子
It's usually given to one ofthe kids from the universities,
但如果你想 我可以给你个面试的机会
but if you want, I could probably get you an interview.
一些入门杂活
There's some entry-level stuff,some gopher work,
但能接触到许多很酷的事
but you'd also have access to a lot of cool things.
谢谢 真的 但 我不能
Thanks, really, but...I can'T.
你可以的
Yes, you can.
Stevie 你很聪明
Stevie, you're bright.
你比大多数的医生有更强的好奇心
You have more curiosity than 90% of the doctors on the staff.
不是那样
Uh...it's not that.
只是...
It's just...
我每天都跟家人一起工作
I go to work every day with my family, you know?
我了解信赖的人
People I've known my whole life.
我不想失去这
I don't want to lose that.
你可以两者兼顾的
You can have both.
不 我不行
No, I can'T.
因为他们不想让你那样
Because they don't want to let you.
他们不应该替你作选择的
They shouldn't be making you choose.
也许不应该 但就是这样
Maybe not, but they are.
我也选择他们
And I'm choosing them.
那 改变是很困难
Look, change is hard.
相信我 我知道
Trust me, I know.
但是对我来说有效
But it worked out for me.
你是个成功的医生
You're a successful doctor.
你的文字印在期刊论文上
Your name is on journal articles.
那有多棒
I would love that.
只是...
It's just...
我看到你 Chase和Cameron医生
I see you with drs.Chaseand cameron, and...
无名指都空空的
you all got empty ring fingers.
你们孤身一人
You're alone.
嚯
Oh ho ho.
我安逸生活的最后一天啦
This is my last day living a life of leisure.
你去告诉Whitner医生让一让位,还是我去?
So are you gonna tell dr.Whitner she's outta my space or can I?
我为什么要去?
Why would I do that?
因为你说了会那么做
Because you said that you would.
而且撒谎是不对的
And lying is wrong.
我说的是如果你整整一礼拜都坐轮椅,我才给你位子--
I said I would give you the space if you made ita whole week--
- 那我-,- 没做到
- which I-,-Didn'T.
打赌没有规定说 你坐轮椅上一星期
The bet didn't stipulate that you had to be in the chair
在迫不得已时 允许你闯入手术室
for a week unless you had to barge into an operating room
揉捏孩子的肠道
and shove your hands in a kid's bowels.
你知道了
You know about that.
你输了
You lost.
我救了一条命
I saved a life.
从轮椅上起身两分钟 救了一个孩子的命
Two minutes out of the chair to save a kid's life.
你输了 house
You lost, house.
我应得到那车位
I earned that space.
不 你不应当
No, you didn'T.
我应得到 因为我每天瘸着进大楼,做我倒霉的工作
I earn that space every day I limp into that building and do my damn job.
你-输-了
You lo-o-ost.
嗨
Hey!
你绝不会给我那个位置 对不对?
You were never gonna give me that space, were you?
我那天遇到Whitner
I saw whitner the other day.
她知道打赌的事
She knew about the bet.
看上去却不担心
Didn't seem that worried.
她知道我会赢
She knew I'd win.
可她不了解我
But she doesn't know me.
事实上 除非你告诉她 她什么都不会知道
In fact, she doesn't know anything except what you tell her,
你告诉她 你绝不会给我这车位 是不是?
and you told her that you were never gonna give me that space, didn't you?
直说
Just tell me.
你难道一点不内疚么
Do you at least feel a little guilty?
如果你想给我点教训,别作你无法实践的承诺
If you wanna teach me lessons, don't make commitments you can't keep.
怎么样?
How's it going?
她看上去有多内疚?
How guilty does she look?
大概有八分
About an eight.
那个车位是我的了
That space is mine.
到 见 胜,(凯撒征服本都后向罗马元老院宣告)
Veni, vidi, vici.